saplinglearning.com 2017-05-23

# Privacy Policy | Sapling Learning

## Sapling Learning Website Privacy Notice

### Effective Date: January 15, 2014  

We at Sapling Learning, Inc. ("we" or "Sapling Learning") respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on www.saplinglearning.com, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information. In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us. We also tell you how you can reach us to update your contact information, contact us with general questions or comments, inquire about our company and its products and services, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices or this website. By logging on to a Sapling Learning website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Notice.

### Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:  

  * **Information We Collect    **  
          Higher Education Users  
          High School Users  
          Both Higher Ed and High School Users  
          Surveys and Questionnaires    
          “Contact Us” and Technical Support  
          Newsletters and Updates  
          Cookies
  * How We Use Information We Collect
  * Information We Share
  * Links to Other Web sites
  * Security
  * Updates to this Privacy Notice
  * How To Contact Us

**Higher Education Users**

To subscribe to Sapling Learning’s online homework and e-book services, higher ed users will either be required to purchase a subscription through our website, or enter the product code from an access card bundled with a print product purchased from a bookstore.  When a purchase is made directly through our website, the purchaser will need to register with PayPal, a third-party service provider we use to process the purchase.  When you do this, you will be their customer as well as ours, and use of your information by PayPal will be governed by their privacy notice, as well as by ours.   Higher ed users will also be required to create an individual account by entering a user name and password, and providing their first and last name, email address, the name of the educational institution at which they are enrolled, and their time zone.  Sapling Learning will maintain such information (other than credit card payment information, which is held directly by our third-party service provider), and in addition, will maintain the user’s course information and homework responses and scores.   In addition, you may choose to provide optional information (e.g., your areas of interest), which will allow us to serve you better.

**High School Users**

To utilize Sapling Learning’s online homework and e-book services, secondary school users will be required to use an assigned user name linked to their school.  At the discretion of the school administrator or other personnel responsible for administering use of Sapling Learning’s services (i) separate user names and passwords may be created for subgroups within the school, and/or (ii) students may have the ability to change their user name and password (but not account number), and enter a city and state and an ID number.  Sapling Learning maintains registration data of high school users and users’ course information and scores.

**Both Higher Ed and High School Users**

Each student generally has access to his or her own work or scores only; instructors can only access work or scores of students in their courses. Protection of information entered by students on the site is controlled by password systems that depend upon both instructors and students keeping their passwords secure. In the event that providing technical or user support requires accessing student work to diagnose or fix the problem, Sapling Learning will request permission from the student and/or instructor involved.

**Surveys and Questionnaires**

We may ask visitors to our Web site to complete online surveys and opinion polls on a variety of topics, such as their activities, attitudes, and interests, and our products and services. These surveys help us understand the needs of our visitors.

**"Contact Us" and Technical Support**

You may choose to contact us through our Web site. If you e-mail us comments or questions, we will have your e-mail address, as well as any other information you choose to provide.

**Newsletters and Updates**

We may use instructor contact information to provide newsletters and updates; users will have the choice of opting out of such communications.  Students will not receive newsletter or updates unless they opt in to such communications.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that Web sites often store on the computer hard drives of visitors to their sites. A cookie contains a unique code, which is used to recognize a computer when a user of that computer returns to a Web site that was visited previously. We use cookies on our Web site, to help us administer certain site features. We may also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests.  The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. However, in order to use certain features of our Web site, users must have the “cookie” function on their browsers enabled.

**Other Passive Collection Information**

When you visit our Web site, your browser automatically sends us certain Internet-related information, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you’re using, your originating domain, your web browser type, and your computer operating system.

Sapling Learning may use standard Internet technology, such as log files, web beacons and other similar technologies to track your use of our sites and software.  If you are a registered user of our Web site, this information may be associated with your user name or id.  Sapling Learning also may include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages and newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.  The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services that are offered to our visitors/customers, to deliver targeted advertisements and to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, programming and other activities.  

**How We Use Information We Collect**

Information collected through our Web site is used in connection with the purpose for which it was submitted (for example, to process your subscription and respond to your requests).

We may also contact you as a user of our products: to ask you to serve as a reviewer; to request an appointment with you at your campus or at a conference to talk about an existing or planned product; and to ask for other similar kinds of feedback and discussion. We may also use the information we collect to send you information or products we think may be of interest to you, and to customize our contacts with you.

Finally, we may use some of the information we collect to analyze Web site use and to do other internal analyses, such as market research, that will allow us to better meet the needs of our customers.

**Information We Share**

We may share the information you provide with companies that are related to Sapling Learning through common ownership. We also share information provided by our Web site visitors with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf, such as our payment processor. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, (ii) in response to legal process, (iii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iv) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses personal information you have provided through this Web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice.

**Links to Other Web sites**

We provide links to other Web sites for your convenience. Also, on occasion, we may provide to a department, program, class or instructor access to a third-party Web site (which may also include access to third-party software). These sites may operate independently from Sapling Learning and may not be under our control. These sites may have their own privacy notices in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked Web sites. We may not be responsible for the content of these sites, any products or services that may be offered through these sites, or the privacy practices of these sites.

**Security**

We use administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect information in our possession and control against foreseeable hazards. Please note, however, that perfect security does not exist on the Internet.  At Sapling Learning, we use a third party service provider to collect your credit card [or debit card] number (and related information). The third party payment service provider will be solely responsible for the collection, use, and storage of your credit card [or debit card] information.

**Updates to this Privacy Notice**

We may change or update portions of this Privacy Notice at any time and without prior notice to you. Please check back from time to time so you are aware of any changes or updates to the Notice. We will indicate above the effective date of the Notice.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about our information practices or our products or services, please contact us by [clicking here](mailto:support@saplinglearning.com) or writing us at:      

Sapling Learning, Inc.  
211 E. 7th Street, 4th Floor  
Austin, Texas 78701  
          Attention:  Support
